The deal is off.
交渉決裂だな
Not that there is much point in telling you now.
と君に言ってもしかたないか　いまさら
Wh-Wh-Why just me...?
な…な…なんで俺だけ
You mean, "Why am I the
only one you didn't shoot?"
俺だけ狙撃されなかったのだ
Well, let's see...
ってのはそうだな
The Mafioso brought drugs for
our transaction instead of money.
私との取引に
金ではなく物を持ってきたマフィア
When he opened the briefcase,
そのあたしが開かれた時
you were the only one who made
a super disgusted face and looked away.
君だけはすんごい嫌そうな顔をしてソイツから目を背けたんだ
That intrigued me, so I didn't kill you.
それが気になったから殺さなかった
That stuff killed my younger brother,
俺の弟はソイツで死んだから
so I may have done that for a split second.
確かに一瞬そうしたかもしれない
But what could I say when
I'm merely the boss' chauffeur?
だからって
ボスの方針に　運転手の俺が何を言えるってんだ
やばい殺される
Crap, I'm going to die!
Besides, what good would
a Mafioso explaining himself do?
もっともマフィアがどう弁明したところで
Why did you look away?
どうして目を背けた
I-I'll leave it to your imagination.
ご…ご想像にお任せします
おう　想像した
I imagined why.
Come with me. I wanted a chauffeur.
うちに来い
運転手がほしかったんだ
ウゴ
Ugo! Ugo!
こ…この野郎
You bastard--!
We have always stood on the borderland.
我們始終踱步於境界線之上
I'm enjoying the view from here.
皆因此境風景獨好
Eeny, meeny, miny, moe...
Eeny,meeny,miny,moe...
一，二，三，四...
much the same
其實都一樣
We have always stood on the borderland.
我們始終踱步於境界線之上
日听   猫日和
框框
I'm enjoying the view from here.
皆因此境風景獨好
翻译  TL旧民
时轴  ZZZ
后期   aoi
神
岛
魔
恶
&
诸
Pike or shield?
Pike or shield?  負けたくはない　でも傷つけたくもない
矛 or 盾？ 不想認輸 可是又不願受傷害
Maketaku wa nai demo kizu tsuketaku mo nai
Te ni totte tashikameteta
手に取って　確かめてた
先挑一樣在手中仔細掂量
Kitto modorenain datte
きっと戻れないんだって
可是發現再要反悔為時已晚
Whose side are you on?
你選的是哪邊？
(Don't want to know!) Omoide wa kase
Don't want to know!  思い出は枷
Don't want to know!  思念是枷鎖
(Don't want to know!) Atozuke no love
Don't want to know!  後付けのlove
Don't want to know!  追悔莫及的愛
(Don't want to know!) Yasashisa wa ada
Don't want to know!  優しさは仇
Don't want to know!  溫柔是弱點
We have always stood on the borderland.
我們始終踱步於境界線之上
Hirogeru ryoute keep balance
広げる両手　keep balance
張開雙臂保持平衡
Yori takaku toberu hou he
より高く飛べる方へ
向著更高的天空振臂而飛
Mamoritai yo
守りたいよ 僕らの翼のないこの背中に背負った
唯獨想保護的是.. 背負於我們那折翼的背膀之上的
Bokura no tsubasa no nai kono senaka ni seotta
Reality and Dream
Reality & Dream
真實 & 夢想
Reality and Dream
Reality & Dream
真實 & 夢想
Reality and Dream
Reality & Dream
真實 & 夢想
I screwed up! It's bulletproof.
しくった　防弾か
It's been two minutes. This is bad.
２分だ　まずいな
Ugo, leave him to me.
ウゴ そいつは俺らに任せて
Roger!
了解
ココを車で連れ出せ
Get Koko away from here via car.
Roger!
はい
Grég, two minutes are up.
グレゴ
２分経った
Grég?!
グレゴ
Grég...?
Grég!
グレーゴー
あっ　し…しま…
Sh...
Shit!
Yikes...!
Ugo, let's go!
ウゴ　行くぞ
There's the third one. Weapons, weapons!
３人目か
武器武器
Little Lady, shall I shake him
and go to the safe house?
お嬢　撒いてセーフハウスに
No! These guys are cautious.
They'll know where it is.
ノーだ　周到な奴らだ
バレてる
Keep racing down Route 1!
このままルートワンを突っ走れ
Little Lady, did you get him?
お嬢　当たった
I missed! I mean, I can't even see him!
当たんない
ってゆーか見えない
That was close! Sh-She's a pretty good shot.
危ね
け…けっこう当ててきますね
And what's with that firepower?
しかもなんだこの威力は
Wasn't it.50 caliber?
This is why I hate targeting arms dealers.
50口径か
これだから武器商など標的に
But they're so riled up that they're accelerating.
でも煽ったおかげでスピードが乗ってきた
I just have to make them crash to kill them.
後は転ばせてやれば死ぬ 任務は完了です
Then the mission will be over!
そろそろ来るな
Any second now.
Little Lady, give me your gun.
お嬢　銃を貸して
Then enter an anti-shock position!
後　対ショック姿勢
Okay!
Bring it on!
おう 上等じゃないっスか
Every so often I need to do something
befitting the Little Lady's driver.
たまにはお嬢の専属運転手らしい仕事をしないと
最悪だ
This sucks. This sucks!
I can't get through.
通じない クソ　何だこの砂漠
Damn, what's wrong with this desert?
Use this!
使え　子分と繋がってるぞ
It's connected to your
subordinates, Boss Dominique.
ボス・ドミニク
ボス ボス
Boss! Boss! Boss Dominique!
ボス・ドミニク
ボス ボス
Liliane!
リリアーヌ
Oh, Boss! The enemy caught me.
あ　ボス 敵に捕まっちゃった
I'm sorry.
ごめんなさい
And Grégoire?
グレゴワールは
Same for Grég. L-Looks like
starting up a restaurant is off.
グレゴも
レ…レストラン無理みたいだね
I expected them to have retreated by now.
当然　逃走完了なものと思ってた
This sucks so bad I feel like I could pass out.
最悪過ぎて気絶しそうだ
You've reached a dead end, Hit Man.
デッドエンドだな　殺し屋
取引してやってもいいぞ
But I'd be willing to make a trade.
I'll let you off.
見逃してやる
その代わり
In exchange, tell me who hired you.
雇い主を言え
You'd be better off running
a restaurant instead of killing people.
殺し屋より　レストランやったほうがいいよ
Jonah, I'm really sorry.
ヨナ君 本当にごめんなさい
But this was the only way...
でもこうするしか
There is no way I could take you along.
君を連れて行けるわけないじゃないですか
But goodness, you are so
kind and quick to take initiative.
それにしても
優しくて行動力があってなかなかいい男ですね　君は
You're a pretty good guy.
If I survive, let's meet again...
生きていたらまた会いましょう
"The Hill of Doom phase.2"
If I survive, let's meet again...
I got up! I was able to
get up because I anticipated it!
起きれた
これをやられると予想していたから起きれた
Twenty minutes.
20分 間に合う
There's still time. I've got to go!
行かなきゃ
Stop! This is private property.
止まれ　ここは私有地だ
Do you have an appointment?
アポイントあるか
The factory isn't open for operation yet.
工場はまだ稼働時間じゃない
何の用だ
What do you want?
Da Xinghai Company!
大星海公司
Go deal with whatever the problem is.
何か知らんが　任せる
Handle it as you will.
好きにしろ
The situation?
状況
Gunfire in the front gate.
We've taken two loses.
発砲は正門
損害２
The intruder is unidentified.
侵入者不明
やられたのか
Were they killed?
One-hit kills with a knife.
ナイフで一撃です
Don't screw with me!
Hurry and find the hostile!
ふざけるな　さっさと探し出せ
Roger!
了解　アッ　女だ
Ah, it's... a woman?!
A white female has infiltrated--!
白人の女が侵入
You still haven't killed off that one woman?
女一人まだ片付けられないのか
もういい
Forget it. I don't expect you to finish her off.
仕留めることは期待せん
Lure her out to where I can see her.
奴を俺の目の前に狩り出せ
狐狩りってのはそういうもんだ
That is how fox hunting works.
あ　この距離から外すってマジか
Huh? I seriously missed from this distance?
Valmet!
バルメ
Jonah?! That's absurd! What's he doing here?
ヨナ君　そんなバカな
何でここに
The drugs I slipped in
his food knocked him out!
私が盛った薬で眠ってたのに
What's taking you so long?
何をもモタモタしているんだ
背中は僕に任せて ボスの首を狩って来い
Leave your back to me
and go take their boss' head!
走れ　走れバルメ
Run! Run, Valmet!
I can hear you, kiddo.
聞こえてるよ　小僧
A boy soldier? Come to think of it,
there was one in that group Karen fought...
少年兵
そういえば　カレンが戦った者の中に
So they're Koko Hekmatyar's
personal soldiers, huh?
ココ・ヘクアティアルの私兵か
I see...
なるほど
Run! Run!
走れ　走れ
Run as I accumulate proof for my
subordinates who fell in this desert
この砂漠で散った部下たちへ贈る
復讐の証明を積み上げながら
that I am avenging them!
I can hear them!
聞こえる
I can hear my subordinates in Heaven!
天国の部下たちが
「感謝します　少佐」と喜ぶ声が
They are happily saying,
"I appreciate this, Major!"
The dead can't rejoice.
死人は喜ばないだろ
No, they are rejoicing.
That is how I raised them.
いいえ　喜びます
そう育てあげましたから
I've finally found you,
Chen Guoming of the Da Xinghai Company!
やっと見つけました
大星海公司　陳国明
You're mighty impudent.
You dare challenge an active general?
頭が高いな
現在の将官に向かって
Aren't you from that UNFID incident,
UNFID の件だな
Major Velmer of the FRDF?
FRDF　ヴェルマーの少佐
You've aged.
老けたな
I doubt I've aged as badly as you have.
そちらほどじゃないと思いますが
That aside, I'm surprised you remember me.
それより私をご存じとは意外でした
I don't remember every
single person who passes away.
この世から消えていく者をいちいち覚えたりはしない
But I remember you well
since I failed to kill you.
だが私は君を撃ち損じたからよく覚えている
This desert factory has been deeply
filled with emotion since your arrival.
君が来たことでこの砂漠の工場が感慨深くなった
The walking course that the
United Nations had assigned to you
国連がかつて君に指定した散歩コースは
has grown into a natural gas field.
こうして天然ガス田に成長したわけだ
Back then, I had one minute
before the second platoon arrived.
あの時
一分で第二小隊が斬てしまう
But it did not feel as though
I had killed you, their boss.
しかし　ボスの君を殺した手応えがなく
君の姿もない
Nor was I able to see you!
It was humiliating.
屈辱だった どこにいたんだ
Where were you?
Oh, I know!
アー　そうか
When one of your men fell on you,
did you hide under his corpse?
上に倒れた部下の死体に隠れていたのか
I had heard that you were a detestable man.
つまらない男だとは聞いてましたが
I see you truly are quite horrid.
相当なものですね　これは
I trained in order to carry out my vengeance,
この報復のため訓練を積んではみましたが
but the more I trained, the closer
my style came to match yours
鍛えれば鍛えるほど
脳裏に刻まれた貴様の技術に似かよっていく
since it was engraved into my head.
But I can stop worrying about that as of today.
悩むのも今日で終わりです
I have formed the resolve to abandon this.
これを捨てる決心がついた
Of course, that's after I finish
tearing the enemy before me to shreds.
目の前の敵を切り刻んだ後の話ですが
ハッカパル
Hakka Päälle!
立て　陳国明
On your feet, Chen Guoming!
I'm going to kill you!
叩き壊してやる
Just as you once killed everything I had!
過去　貴様が私のすべてをそうしたように
Don't you mean "crush"?
叩き壊す いいじゃないか
You should be grateful, Major.
感謝しろ少佐
By losing everything, you obtained
the true essence of a soldier.
お前はすべてを失うことで軍人の本質を手にした
私は走れはしないが 侮るなよ
I may not be able to run,
but do not underestimate me.
Severing your head will be a piece of cake!
首を刎ねることくらい造作もない
Hot!
暑っ
What is it?
なんだ
K-Karen, it's terrible!
Executive Director Chen and the staff are...
か…カレンさん 大変です
陳専務やスタッフの方々が…
Shaojiang!
少将
少将　少将
Shaojiang! Shaojiang!
Shaojiang!
少将
I won't let you escape!
逃すか
Thanks.
あ…ありがとう
バルメ
Valmet?
What is it, Jonah?
何ですか　ヨナ君
Let's go back to Koko and the others.
ココたちの所へ帰ろう
Valmet? Valmet?!
I-I... I'm sick of this world!
こ…こ…こんな世界もう嫌だ
Good morning, Valmet!
Good  Morning　　バルメ
Koko...?
ココ
Good morning.
おはようございます
What are you doing?
何やってんの
You got hit by two.45 caliber
rounds there and on your thigh.
そこと右太股計2発の45口径をくらってる
Jonah's emergency treatment saved your life.
ヨナの応急処置で命拾いしたんだ
You should be grateful.
感謝しないとね
You cut your hair...
髪切ったのか
But don't you look best with it
long or super short like old times?
でもバルメは伸ばすか
昔見たいなショートのほうがよくない
あ　あのう　ココ
Uh, Koko? Aren't you mad?
怒ってないんですか
Eh? I'm pissed. Does it show?
え　怒ってるよ
やっぱ分かる
Just look at that bed!
The sheets are even nicely tucked in!
見てよ　あのベッド
シーツもきっちり畳まれて
That's where the woman who shot you stayed.
バルメを撃った女がここにいた
It was Lieutenant Karen Low
of the Da Xinghai Company.
大星海公司　カレン・ロウ中尉だ
She vanished...
彼女は消えた
...just like smoke.
煙のように
Man, this bites! Hush money for the doctors!
あーん　もうすごいぞ
ドクター　口止め料
Hush money for army helicopter transportation!
軍のヘリで移送　口止め料
Hush money to hide Jonah's very existence!
ヨナの存在　口止め料
Hush money for the stuff you destroyed!
その他　いろいろ壊したからな　口止め料
On top of all that, I have to
cover Karen Low's hospital fees!
その上　アイツの治療費まで私持ちかい　カレン・ロウ
ってこと
That's all I'm angry about.
その件だけだよ
私の怒りは
That's why the doctors are making such a fuss.
医者がドタバタしているのはそのせいで
They should be coming to say,
"Pay for her," any minute now.
そろそろ来るぞ 「アイツの分　払って」って
This incident included terrorist activity
今回の件でさ
テロ実行
and terrorist instigation and support.
テロ教唆　支援
We are becoming remarkably evil.
我らは尋常ならざる悪になりつつあるな
Major Velmer, I am of one mind on this.
ヴェルマー少佐
私が思うのは１つだ
The souls of all your
subordinates who fell in the desert
砂漠に散った部下の魂はすべてフィンランドに帰った
have returned to Finland.
You did not leave a single one of them behind.
あなたは一人も置き去りにはしなかったのだ
I admire you, Major.
尊敬します　少佐
悪党の賛辞で恐縮ですが
I hope you don't mind that coming from a villain.
Koko, Koko!
ココ　ココ　んーッ
What are you doing? Really!
何やってんの　もう
Now then, Major Velmer
has completed her mission.
さて　ヴェルマー少佐は務めを果たした
So what will Valmet do?
それで　バルメは
I fully belong to you, Koko!
完全に私のすべてはココのものですよ
That's a relief!
安心した
Hurry and get better.
早く傷を治したまえ
And here is your tool of the trade.
それと　仕事道具だ
You'll need it, won't you?
必要でしょ
It's time I left.
I'll come back and visit you later.
時間だから
じゃね　また来るから
Don't go crazy on them here.
暴れたりするんじゃないぞ
Oh, right, right. About what I said.
あ　そうそう
さっきの続き
I think you should grow your
hair out in light of everything.
髪は伸ばしたほうがいいな
いろいろなこと踏まえて
I just thought I'd mention that.
って言ってみただけ
Miss Hekmatyar, if you will--
ミス・へクマティアル あのですね
Yeah, yeah! I'm going to pay you!
はいはい 払いますよ
And...
それと
I'll pay up!
払います
You were attacked by hit men again?
また殺し屋に襲われたのか
又被殺手襲擊了嗎？
Uh-huh, uh-huh!
What were they like?
Are there any casualties?
どんな奴
什麼樣的傢伙？
けが人は
有人受傷嗎？
They were like street performers...
大道芸人みたいな
類似雜耍藝人那樣的？
They were weirdos!
変な奴らだったね
反正是很奇怪的一群人
As for casualties,
けが人は　レームが軽い傷
受傷人員嘛 雷姆受輕傷
Lehm was lightly injured
and Lutz got knifed in the butt.
ルツがお尻にナイフ
魯茲屁股上中刀
ルツまた尻か
魯茲又是傷屁股啊
Lutz and his butt.
So close! I missed your smile!
惜しい　ヨナの笑い顔見逃した
真可惜 錯過了約拿的笑容
It was one of the few times
I intentionally let it slip by.
私にしては珍しく逃がしてやったけどね
不過我放了他們一馬呢 對我來說真是難得
The problem is their client.
問題はその雇い主
問題是他們的雇主..
Huh? The hit men told
you who their client was?
え　殺し屋が雇い主を喋ったの
誒？殺手供出了雇主？
I know, right? Isn't that weird?
そうなの　おかしいでしょ
就是啊 很奇怪吧
But I don't really care.
ま　どうでもいいけどね
嘛 隨便它去啦
I gave Lehm and the others leave
and we'll regroup for the next job.
レームたちには休みを上げて　次の仕事で集合だけど
我讓雷姆他們放假 下次工作的時候再集合
I'll be okay with you around, Jonah!
ヨナがいるから大丈夫
不過因為有約拿在所以我很放心
今回の件　すばらしい働きだった
這次的事情 你幹的非常漂亮
You did a wonderful job in this last incident!
I didn't really do anything.
別に僕は何にもしてないよ
我什麼都沒幹啦
ご褒美をあげる　何でも言って
我要給你獎賞 要什麼盡管說吧
I'm going to reward you.
Ask for anything you want!
I'm hungry.
お腹が空いた
肚子餓了
Doctor, that busty patient
is doing muscle training!
先生　例の巨乳の患者さん筋トレしてます
醫生！那個巨乳的患者小姐在鍛煉肌肉！
Wh-What?!
ナッ何に
納尼？！
I can't believe she has two holes in her!
風穴二つあけてるのに　信じられない
明明身上穿了兩個大洞 真不敢相信！
Stop her instead of throwing a fit!
キャーキャー言う間に止めんか
有時間在這裡大叫不如快點阻止她！
華盛頓郊外
Good morning.
おはようございます
Morning!
おはよう
Daddy, stop dumping your sweaty
clothes in front of the bathroom!
パパ シャワールームの前に汗だくの服散らかすのやめてよね
Did you step on them?
踏んだ
Mama, you say something, too!
ママ　何か言ってやってよ
I swear, you make cooking feel worthwhile.
まったく作りがいがあるわ
アンタらの飯はよく食うわ
You have such big appetites!
Well, I'm off.
んじゃ　行ってくんね
Bookman!
ブックマン
Hey!
You have impeccable timing.
We're canceling today's Operation Undershaft.
ちょうどよかった
今日のオペレーション・アンダーシャフトは中止だ
I have to fly out and there
isn't much time until my flight.
飛ぶ用事ができてフライトまで時間がないんだ
So sorry, but could you
pass that along to everyone?
悪いけど皆に伝えてくれない
What? That's why I got up early!
なんだよ　そのために早起きしたのに
Sorry.
スマンね
Good morning.
おはよう
Good morning, Director Black.
おはようございます
ブラック課長
--Did you get the tickets?
--I did.
チケ取れた
はい
Then please take me to the Dulles Airport.
じゃ　ダレス空港まで送ってください
Very well.
了解しました
Director, may I ask you something?
課長　１つお聞きしたいのですが
What is it?
なに
Why do your coworkers refer
to you as a scholar--Bookman?
ご同僚の方々に学者「ブックマン」と呼ばれるのはなぜです
I can speak Arabic.
アラビア語喋れるんだけどさ
It's because I majored in
Ancient Arabic back in college.
大学で古典アラビア語専攻してたからなんだよ
Wouldn't that make me a scholar?
だから「学者」ってことじゃない
Middle Easterners refer to me
as Adeeb, a man of letters.
中東の人からも文学者「アディーブ」とか言われたりする
I had wanted to become a scholar
of Arabic history, really.
アラビアの歴史学者になりたかったんだ　本当は
Italians call me Burattinaio, the puppeteer.
イタリア人は「ブラッティナイオ」人形遣いって呼んだりするし
I have so many nicknames that
I forget what my real name is!
あだ名だらけで自分の名前忘れてしまうよ
まさかぁ
I doubt that!
No, I'm not joking. I really mean it!
いやいや 冗談じゃなくて　本当本当
そろそろ空港です　課長
We will be arriving at the airport soon, Director.
Hikari yokotaeru wadatsumi
光横たえる海神
光怪陸離的海底龍神
Soukon no ma ni yurameku ayamachi
創痕の間に揺らめく過ち
累累創痕之間搖曳著縷縷罪孽
Fujou shite iki wo tsugi
浮上して息を継ぎ
浮出水面 吸清吐濁
Tokasare majiru dake no zouai wo te ni shita
溶かされ混じるだけの憎愛を手にした
愛與恨 如漆似膠 如影隨形
Mujun haramu
矛盾孕む
矛盾誕生
Kono sekai goto
この世界ごと 覆い尽くしてる策動の音に傾く夢
冥冥的夢中 世界漸漸傾浸於欺言詭語之中
Ooitsukushiteru sakudou no ne ni katamuku yume
Ashi wa mou nai
脚は　もう無い
足膝 已沒入虛無
Suiheki wo tsuranuku kodou
水壁を貫く鼓動
透過水壁 傳來陣陣鼓動
恶魔岛字幕组(bbs.emland.net)
诸神字幕组(kamigami.org)
Koko Hekmatyar is currently in Alexandria.
ココ・へクマティアルが今アレクサンダリアだから
Did he choose to meet me in
Paris since it's our midpoint?
中間時点のパリで落ち合おうということなのか
It looks like he's matured enough
to be considerate of others.
気が遣えるほどには成長したみたいだな
Sorry! Did I keep you waiting, Saw?
悪いね
待ったかい　ソウ
Yeah, for quite a while.
うん　かなり待った
It's been ages, Saw.
久しぶりだな　ソウ
I'm glad to see you're well, R.
元気そうで何よりだ　アール
本字幕由   恶魔岛字幕组   &   诸神字幕组   联合制作
(bbs.emland.net)    (kamigami.org)
日听 猫日和        日听 框框
翻译 TL旧民        校对 YAYA
后期 aoi         时轴 ZZZ
仅供交流学习之用 禁止用于商业用途
诸神字幕组
恶魔岛字幕组